

WEB/SOFTWARE DEVELOPER · DATA SCIENTIST · ENGINEER

201, 48 Concession St., Kingston, ON, Canada, K7K 2A6

□ 343-333-4396 | ☑ chenshulun@gmail.com | □ shulun | □ shulunchen

Objective .

A highly skilled and enthusiastic developer and an engineering physics graduate from Queen's university who has in the past built simple arcade games with Python, earthquake map and text-editing applications with Java, restaurant websites and mobile applications with multiple web frameworks and android tools. Furthermore, he has extensive experiences in solving complicated mathematical, physics and computing problems using many techniques from numerical analysis and modelling.

Skills _____

Programming Languages	Python, Java, JavaScript, MATLAB, C, Mathematica, R
Dyo gyo maning Chille	Object Oriented Design and Analysis, Test-driven Development,
Programming Skills	Hardware Control, LaTex, Microsoft Office Suite
Version Control	GitHub
Operating Systems	Windows, Linux, Android
Engineering Programs	MATLAB, Solid Edge, Google SketchUp, COMSOL
Soft Skills	Effective communicator, Team player, Leadership,
	Time management, Perform well under pressure

Experience _

Restaurant Website and Mobile Application Design

Kingston, ON

PART-TIME WEB DEVELOPER

Jun. 2016 - Aug. 2016

- Set up a responsive website featuring a restaurant using Bootstrap and its components.
- Used Bower and NPM to retrieve packages and organize them into JSON files.
- · Utilized Less and Sass to customize CSS codes.
- Adopted Grunt and Gulp to construct the restaurant website project.
- Employed modal-view-controller (MVC) design pattern to implement website user interface.
- Launched functional front-end web applications using AngularJS.
- Performed unit testing and E2E testing on codes with Karma and Protractor.
- Built a restaurant mobile application targeting iOS/Android platforms with a single codebase.
- Used various features of Ionic framework to build a hybrid mobile application that could be run on Andoid phones.

Earthquake Map and Text Editor Application Design

Kingston, ON

PART-TIME SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Apr. 2016 - Jul. 2016

- Designed an interactive map with Java and Processing that used data collected from USGS to display updated earthquakes around the world.
- Coded a simple text editor GUI with Java that provided many standard functionalites such as auto-complete and auto-correct which allowed users to refine their texts, as well as Flesch score calculation and playable word games.
- Adopted test-driven development and wrote test codes for all the applications above to ensure good performance.

Web-based Arcade/Puzzle Game Design

Kingston, ON

PART-TIME WEB GAME DEVELOPER

Jul. 2015 - Oct. 2015

- Built arcade/puzzle games such as Pong, Zombie Apocalypse, Asteroids, 2048 and many others that could be played on browsers with Python.
- Implemented a simple GUI and tests to further polish the games and secure the game flow.

Undergraduate Robot Design Project

Kingston, ON

FULL-TIME UNDERGRADUATE STUDENT Sep. 2013 - Dec. 2013

- · Worked in a team to design an autonomous air-hockey robot that was capable of playing against human players.
- Used a high-speed PlayStation eye camera to track puck movement with RoboRealm software.
- Employed x-y arms, rail carts, pulley systems, H bridge driven DC motors to construct the robot.
- · Coded PID control of the robot with C and Arduino IDE.

Undergraduate Thesis Project

Kingston, ON

FULL-TIME UNDERGRADUATE STUDENT

Sep. 2013 - Apr. 2014

- Finished a complete design of the PLEC test-box, including the circuit/temperature control and mechanical components.
- Coded the circuit/temperature feedback control systems with C.
- Compiled a detailed thesis report on the entire design.

Graduate Project Kingston, ON

FULL-TIME GRADUATE STUDENT

May. 2016 - Jun. 2016

- · Wrote image analysis programs that performed simple object boundary recognition and distance measurements with MATLAB.
- Coded programs that operated the control systems of lab equipment with LabView.
- · Used COMSOL to conduct a finite element analysis of the device studied to support experimental results.

Honors _____

AWARDS

2013	Dean's Honor List , Queen's University	Kingston, ON
2012	Dean's Honor List, Queen's University	Kingston, ON
2011	Dean's Honor List, Queen's University	Kingston, ON

CERTIFICATES

2015	Intercultural Competence Certificate, Queen's University International Center	Kingston, ON
2015	Standard CPR & First Aid, ISLAND Aid	Kingston, ON

Education

Queen's University

Kingston, ON

B.S. IN ENGINEERING PHYSICS

Sep. 2010 - Apr. 2014

- GPA: 3.6, Science 95 Bursary Awardee
- · Dean's Honor List, First Class Graduate

Queen's University

Kingston, ON

M.Sc. IN ENGINEERING PHYSICS

Sep. 2014 - present

• Graduate Travel Award

Publications

Queen's University

Kingston, ON

CHEMELECTROCHEM

Oct. 2015

OCTOBER 21, 2016 SHULUN CHEN · RÉSUMÉ

Solid-State Bipolar Electrochemistry: Polymer-Based Light-Emitting Electrochemical Cells: link